[Music]
so let's look at an example of
computing the mass using line integrals
so we have the following example which
is a wire is in the shape of a circle of
radius 2
centered in the origin let's say and has
density function
rho which is 2 plus 1 half x
we want to find the mass of the wire now
of course the mass is given by the line
integral over the curve c
of the density function and so we first
have to parameterize the wire
and we'll do that by using the function
alpha t which is
2 sine t in the x component and 2
cosine t in the y component and we'll
vary t
from minus pi to pi now with respect to
this parametrization we see
that rho is just two plus sine t
in particular the line integral over the
curve c of rho of x
y d s is just the integral from minus pi
to pi
of two plus sine t that's just rho with
respect to the parametrization
and then the arc length term is just the
square root of 4
cosine squared t plus 4 sine squared t
dt the pythagorean identity of course
tells us that cosine
squared plus sine squared t is one so
we're left with the integral from minus
pi to pi
of two times two plus sine t dt
which is just two times two t minus
cosine t
from minus pi to pi and this expands to
two times two pi minus cosine of pi
minus two times minus pi plus cosine of
minus pi
of course since cosine of pi is minus
one and cosine of minus pi is also
minus 1. what we're left with is 2 times
pi plus 1 plus 2 pi minus 1
and this is just 8 pi
you